

CONOR DOHERTY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **DETAILS**

Apartment 1, Tates Mews 13 Tates Avenue BT9 7BY Belfast

<u>+44 7889 789348</u> conordoherty97@hotmail.com

### LINKS

**Portfolio** 

GitHub

## **EDUCATION**

Queen's University Belfast (2016-2021)

Bachelor of Science in Computing & IT with a Year in Industry

Graduated with high 2:2

St Joseph's Boys' School, Derry (2009-2016)

A-Level Engineering: A\*
A-Level ICT: B
A-Level Business Studies: B
8 GCSEs Grades (A-C)
including English &
Mathematics

### **SKILLS**

**HTML & CSS** 

PHP

JAVASCRIPT

REACT JS

JAVA

\_\_\_

SQL

**PYTHON** 

### **PROFILE**

I have 2 years' professional experience in the IT industry. I wish to pursue a career in Software Development. I believe starting off as a graduate would be a huge opportunity for me to learn new skills and enhance qualities required to fulfil this career choice.

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

### User Support Technician, Queen's University Belfast

JULY 2021 - PRESENT

- Assisting staff members with product selection based on stated needs, proposed use, and budget.
- Activating accounts for staff members.
- Helping to streamline repair processes and update procedures for support action consistency.
- Processing over 100 support requests weekly for technical assistance on a wide range of issues related to all QUB services.
- Providing Tier 1 IT support to non-technical students & staff members through desk side support services. I can communicate easily with all levels of staff and students.
- Explaining technical information in clear terms to non-technical users to provide them with a better understanding.
- Installing, modifying, and repairing software and hardware to resolve technical issues.
- Removing malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Configuring hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for staff.
- Creating and maintaining Information Services webpages.

# **Computer Assistant Placement, Queen's University Belfast**

*AUGUST 2019 – AUGUST 2020* 

- Assessed system hardware and software and suggested modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- Responded to support requests from end users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Tested and installed motherboards, processors and graphics cards on desktops and laptops for corporate staff.
- Imaged and prepared new computers for integration into company networks and systems.
- Linked computers to network and peripheral equipment.
- Refurbished PC systems and peripherals such as monitors, networking equipment, printers and more.
- Explained technical information, in clear terms, to non-technical individuals to provide them with a better understanding.

#### **PROJECTS & PRACTICALS**

### Web Development

- I created a Virtual Learning Environment (VLE) with the use of HTML5, PHP and JavaScript.
- I have created an online hardware store that shows stock availability of different shops nearby. This website involves a booking system, review system, 'Click & Collect' system and stock levels & prices in different stores. For this project I have used HTML, SQL, PHP, CSS & JavaScript
- I have also created News Blog Website using Phalcon PHP.
- Maintenance of 'Moville Clothing' website which runs on BigCommerce.
- I created my own personal website which will be used as a portfolio using WordPress.
- I created a website as an alternative to 'IMDb' & 'Rotten Tomatoes'. I used HTML, SQL, PHP, CSS & JavaScript.
- I created a customer Admin Dashboard using React JS. This project showcases different widgets and interactive charts that show the statistics of sales, profits etc. This project also features a 'light & dark' mode.
- I created a replica of Facebook using React JS & Material UI. This project displays posts, online friends, notifications & recent messages. This project also features a 'light & dark' mode.
- I created a front-end website that could be used as a template for a portfolio. This website was created using React JS and Tailwinds CSS.

## System Administration & Maintenance

- I studied the hardware of a PC and have dismantled and upgraded all components to ensure it was able to load up correctly without any problems.
- Within this module I have learned the basics of Linux OS.

### SQL

• I created a database management system for Queen's Accommodation which enables the users to keep track of their properties, tenants, and employees. I used complex SQL queries to build the database, insert data and retrieve specific data which needed to be returned.

# **PRACTICALS**

- I have completed a Database module using SQL to create a schema, tables and then populate the tables using SQL queries. As part of the project, I used very complex queries to produce specific information.
- In level 2, my Software Engineering module taught me HTML, PHP, CSS and touched on JavaScript. I learned how to create a fully functional website and was able to upload it to my own personal server within Queen's University. I used FileZilla to upload my work to the server.
- In level 3, my Data Analysis and Visualisation module has taught me the basics of R programming. My Software Testing module taught me different ways to test software using white-box testing and black-box testing. My Contemporary Team-based Computing Project taught me how to work within a team to create and deploy an application/program used in the real software industry. The Network Security module taught me in more depth about networks and cyber security. Finally, my final year project enabled me to use my own initiative to study a certain topic to complete the necessary requirements, in order to write my program with HTML, CSS, PHP & JavaScript.

# **REFERENCES**

References available upon request.